[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking to Mr. Ray Hayworth in his den, and what I like to do in these interviews is usually start in right with the beginning, where you were born and what the family background was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm talking to Mr. Ray Hayworth in his den, and what I like to do in these interviews is usually start in right with the beginning,
[SPEAKER_01]: where you were born and what the family background was and how you grew up and first played ball and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: So if you'd start right in on that, that would be fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I can begin by saying that I grew up about 20 minutes from my home here, right near Springfield down here, which is a Quaker settlement.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all my line of people are Quakers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as I grew up around Springfield, even in
[SPEAKER_00]: Great school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Baseball was everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: All the kids played baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had leagues here at that time at every crossroads, every furniture factory mill had a baseball team.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we kind of grew up in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I might say this at the outset, in my early years, I grew up in kind of a baseball family.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were four of us brothers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all of us played professionally, and all four of us were catchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my brother, Red, followed me, which he's a younger member of our family, on into St. Louis, and he played, caught in the 44 World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: But getting back to my early days in, as I recall, around Springfield and south of High Point here, was really sort of the foundation of our baseball
[SPEAKER_00]: beginning.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was so interesting.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had one old gentleman here they called Rubell, he was the Duke of Spiro, and he was a great left-hand pitcher in this area.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sort of was our father along the way, and we all followed him and created so much interest in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you live on a farm, the family?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, we had a not too large a farm.
[SPEAKER_00]: My dad was a tobacco farmer and raised cotton.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was a merchant for many years at a store.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he play any ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never played in his life.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't know a thing about baseball until we began playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, of course, he became intensely interested in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: My mother, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they get to see you play in the big leagues?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, they used to come up to Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: My mother was up at the 34 World Series in Detroit, 35.
[SPEAKER_00]: They really got to see some of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just want to check and see how we're coming.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, you hear about boys raised on the farm begin throwing rocks at tin cans?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that's where we developed our squirrel hut, throwing rocks at squirrels and one thing or another.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I guess it does help to develop kids' arms according to the way you grew up.
[SPEAKER_00]: But fortunately,
[SPEAKER_00]: My brothers as well as myself, nature gave all four of us good strong arms.
[SPEAKER_00]: We could all throw, which was very important, important in catching.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we never had great foot speed.
[SPEAKER_00]: The reason I'm saying these things, I learned so many of these things that you look for in all my years of scouting following my playing career.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as time went on, I played in high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eventually went to Oak Ridge Prep School close by here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Excuse me, did they have a team in high school?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I played in high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Believe it or not, I pitched in high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when I went to Oak Ridge, I began catching all together.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my second year old, I signed with Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this Oak Ridge, was this an academy somewhat corresponding to high school years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, it was a preparatory, it's more of a preparatory school for college.
[SPEAKER_00]: You come off of high school.
[SPEAKER_00]: I left high school in the 10th grade and went over there and completed my schooling there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't go on to college because I chose to go into professional baseball at that point.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did sign with Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at that time, they put a lot of their kids out at Bluefield, West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played out there two years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rick Sarl and a group of us at Detroit had signed, which they
[SPEAKER_00]: was due then, it was sort of head of the farm system.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played there, and then I came on with Detroit in 26, my first year in professional ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about all these players coming out of this area now.
[SPEAKER_01]: The academy there, I guess?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Colonel Holt, the coach over there, which is highly regarded during his lifetime as one of the best coaches in the country, even though he was in prep school.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sent many players to the major leagues from there, J.K. May and Wes Ferrell, my brother Red.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, in fact, my brother Red was the ninth player that he sent to the major leagues from that little prep school.
[SPEAKER_00]: And many other fellows went out of there and played.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it was such a fun place.
[SPEAKER_00]: And every kid in this country wanted to go to school at Oak Ridge.
[SPEAKER_00]: They began seeing these fellows go out of there in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so I just... How do you account for that?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a chance, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's one generation producing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at that time, when I moved into professional baseball, there were so many fellows right out of this immediate area.
[SPEAKER_00]: Larry Woodall, Hoot Gibson, old Sam Gibson, the knuckleballer, and a great many fellows like the Ferrells.
[SPEAKER_00]: where slaughter came on a little bit later.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I know at one time we sat down and counted all the fellows from this area in here over about a 10-year period, and we could have gotten a major league club out of this immediate vicinity here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think that was due to the fact, as I mentioned there briefly earlier, that so many fellows, kids, played ball in this area then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And wherever there's a great deal of baseball play, prospects come out of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: We learned that in later years in scouting that after we had covered the country here, we began going to Cuba and Puerto Rico and Panama and Dominican Republic because the kids down there, they played ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's all they ever do is play ball and get a stick and make a ball and get out and play.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't have other sports which take the attention of the boys here?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: They realize down there it's going on today that there's a great opportunity in baseball and they just go all out for it and that's all they do is play.
[SPEAKER_01]: So... What year was it you finished up at the academy?
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that the...
[SPEAKER_00]: In 25.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 26 I went spring training with Detroit State.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, sorry.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Benidorm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Benidorm made one trip through this country one spring.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stopped off at Wake Forest, signed Vic Sorrell,
[SPEAKER_00]: He came through here, and I signed with Detroit at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went on out to Tennessee and got Dale Alexander and Johnny Stone.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got us an array of players, and every one of us wound up in Detroit playing up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He saw you play here with the academy team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes, at Oak Ridge.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he come and seek you out or go to your family?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he visited with us, mainly through the coach at Oak Ridge.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had an opportunity to go to Wake Forest to school, but at that time all I could see was baseball and I just sort of lived and admired fellas I'd read about all my life like Ty Cobb and Trish Speaker and Eddie Collins and Babe Ruth and all of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I got to go up there and play against these fellas.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember the day, the first day I was in a ballgame, got to hit against Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought that was the greatest thing there was.
[SPEAKER_01]: But did your parents want you to go on to college, or how did they feel about it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they didn't push college too much because I really didn't turn in that direction.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just wasn't interested at that point in going to college.
[SPEAKER_00]: And fortunately, I went right on into professional ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd they feel about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they have to sign?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you engaged to sign?
[SPEAKER_01]: They signed for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was the idea to go right up and you went to the Tigers right away?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 26, and I stayed up there nearly all year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about that now.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did it feel like going up to the big city there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you how this happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Toronto, their AAA club in Detroit, both trained at Augusta, Georgia.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went down with the Toronto club, Vic Sorrell and I, and we went through spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I caught a few games in Toronto.
[SPEAKER_00]: And unfortunately at that point for the Detroit club, but fortunately for me, Johnny Baxter broke his leg.
[SPEAKER_00]: Baxter?
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny Baxter was their number one catcher in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And after he broke his leg, they were looking around.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they had seen me in spring training and Ty Cobb said, well let's just bring that kid over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: and let him stay here until Bassler gets back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Bassler didn't come back until August.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the meantime, after I got up there, Larry Woodall was the other catcher, and he got a terrible spike wound in his knee.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they looked around, and I'm all that's left sitting there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I began catching some game, and I got along real well.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a great experience for me, because I knew after playing up there that I had no need to go out and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next year they sent me to Nashville with Jimmy Hamilton.
[SPEAKER_00]: I stayed there until July.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went over to Shreveport in the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_00]: I finished 27 there and played there in 28.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a good year, 28.
[SPEAKER_00]: And went on back to Detroit for spring training next year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at the close of spring training, just prior to opening the season, Bucky Harris was our manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wanted me to go down to Toledo and play with Casey Stengel.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, Casey will teach you to hit the right field, hit and run, and things you're going to need to do to compete up here.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went on down there with Casey.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wound up with a great year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit 330, went back to Detroit, and was there almost 10 years before I was sold to Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was it like going up there in 26?
[SPEAKER_01]: And here's Ty Cobb, your manager now.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you think?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was a great thrill for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And two, at that point, I had read so much about the stars up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mentioned a while ago Eddie Collins and Trist Speaker and Walter Johnson and all the old timers that were around the league then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And seeing them was a great thrill to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then getting to actually play against them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so I did a
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot for me, it made me want to get ready to play up there more than ever.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did Cobb deal with you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Ty Cobb, I've been asked that question many times.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the most fierce competitor on the field that I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't do anything to beat you.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the nicest, mildest fellow to sit in the hotel lobby and visit with that you would ever want to meet.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could never put the two of them together
[SPEAKER_00]: And I used to listen to him talk, which they did a great deal in those days.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd sit around the lobby and talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to listen to the great stories Cobb would tell about base stealing and how they sharpened their spikes, which went on back in those days.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other team would walk by the dugout.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was pleasantly surprised.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was very nice to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He knew I was just a young kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we developed a friendship that lasted all through the years as long as he lived.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And other people in Detroit at that time were nice to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Garinger was just coming on, great career ahead of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And our Detroit teams, our great teams in there, 34 and 35 and on, began to be put together in a 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: Players coming up from the Texas League, 33 and 34, Jojo White and Schoolboy Rowe and Tommy Bridges.
[SPEAKER_00]: All those fellows were just coming on.
[SPEAKER_00]: We all kind of grew up together there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when they were able to make the addition of Mickey Cochran and Goose Gosling, adding them to Hank Greenberg and Charlie Garinger and Marv Owens and Pete Fox and the great pitchers we had in there at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ellen Hawker and Hogsett and Sorrell and Crowder and Rowe and Bridges.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll tell you, it was such a pleasure to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just went every day nearly.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went two out of three days.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I learned how nice it was to play on a championship club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I learned later how disappointing it was to play on a second division club.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I had a taste of it all the way around.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me, do you remember the scandal at the end of the 26th season where Cobb and Speaker had to quit and leave?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember much about that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember, yes, but not the details.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Cobb had to, he resigned as manager rather early, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he resigned that year, and of course he went on to Philadelphia with Connie Mack and played a little more,
[SPEAKER_00]: He was near the end of his career then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Believe it or not, the year I was born in 1904, Ty Cobb was playing in Detroit, and I finally grew up and got up there to play with him before he finished there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it is...
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you with them in 27?
[SPEAKER_02]: You weren't with them though, so...
[SPEAKER_01]: I was trying to get at here how the club felt.
[SPEAKER_01]: after he was gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Donnie Bush manage in 27?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder what the change in managers would be.
[SPEAKER_00]: Moriarty came in there and managed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then following that, Bucky Harris came on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played for Cobb there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bucky Harris and Mickey Cochran, Dale Baker, all were the managers when I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I really played for some great managers, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went on to Brooklyn and played
[SPEAKER_00]: with DeRosier, Bill Terry in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who's at the top of your list?
[SPEAKER_00]: Southworth in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I thought Southworth was a great manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't with him too long.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bucky Harris was a good manager, a good, solid manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And DeRosier was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember Mr. Rickey saying in a meeting one time that DeRosier could make decisions faster
[SPEAKER_00]: than any manager he ever knew, you know, how rapidly the situation changes during the course of a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And DeRosier was right there every second.
[SPEAKER_00]: He admired him for that, so he really liked DeRosier so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh... Their lifestyles weren't exactly the same.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Much different at night and day, but...
[SPEAKER_01]: He recognized his ability.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, DeRosier was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Ty, did you get much chance to see Ty Cobb in the managerial role?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think Ty was such a great star, and he expected so much from his men because he was so great himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: Other people like Southworth and Mickey Cochran and all, they had different turns to them in managing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's just hard to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were all good managers, but I just feel like that one or two of them were so outstanding in my mind.
[SPEAKER_01]: It seems to be often the way a great player turned manager doesn't do that well, and the great managers are those who were never great players.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to quote Mr. Rickey again.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a great admiration for Mr. Rickey because I played for him, broke in scouting under him, and he analyzed the game so thoroughly.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said one time about managers,
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, there is no way in the world to tell whether a fellow can manage or not, can become a manager, until you give him a club and put him on the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you can find out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Meaning that you couldn't take a star and say, well, he'll be a great manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of our great managers, some of them never played major league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Walter Alston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Walter Alston, and McCarthy, and New York, and a lot of those fellows.
[SPEAKER_00]: Managers are a rare breed of people, and you just can't tell, as Mr. Rickey used to say, until you give them the opportunity to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of a chap was Dale Alexander?
[SPEAKER_00]: Great man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just thought, I roomed with Dale for several years, and he was a mild-mannered, easy-going fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, he could swing that bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: He left our club in Detroit, went to Boston, led the American League, and hit him when he was as slow as a snozzin' Marty.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he...
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess the... was it Harry Davis came up?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if they'd kept him though.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Dale was a real gentleman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the finest character you'd ever want to meet.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to come over here to see me in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went home with him one year after the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Spent a week with that squirrel out in Midland and stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he and Johnny Stone and fellas like that, I was with in Detroit, Tommy Bridges, all of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were Tennesseans up there, weren't there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, a lot of ballplayers come out of Tennessee.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mentioned Johnny Gill.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you with him at some time?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with him in Shreveport, Louisiana, the Texas League, and he later went up to Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember the day he left the club down there to join Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had his big suitcase with two bats strapped on the outside of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a, everybody in baseball thought a great deal of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had such a great sense of humor.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just was the most likable kind of a fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: But along the way you met so many individuals that were so different.
[SPEAKER_00]: naturally all over the country.
[SPEAKER_00]: But some of the best friends I had came on later, like Lavegetto and people like that in Brooklyn that I got to know real well and associated with.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, tell me a little bit about Nashville.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I went to Nashville with Jimmy Hamilton.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I played there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had an outstanding catcher at that time named Leo Mackey.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I just wasn't getting any chance to work at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was trying to be independent.
[SPEAKER_00]: Naturally, they were independent from where I was going along.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he had a friend over in Texas League at Shreveport named Art Phelan.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Art needed a catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I wanted to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they just sent me over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll just tell you quickly a most unusual story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell us slowly.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went over there and it was as hot as blazes down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was all day ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't start off too good there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was so hot until I got in shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I played down there two or three weeks and finally they called up and said,
[SPEAKER_00]: told Detroit, called Jack Zeller, and he said, what about this Hayworth boy?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, he's not doing too well.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, well, just give him his release.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we went on a road trip right at that time, down to San Antonio.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had the hottest streak I ever had in my life baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit a bunch of home runs and hit something with the bases loaded.
[SPEAKER_00]: After they had told him to release me,
[SPEAKER_00]: The giant scout was following our club, and he saw me play and have that hot streak.
[SPEAKER_00]: New York immediately called up Sreeport and offered $50,000 for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They called up Detroit and said, Evans, don't release him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that year I finished up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next year I had a good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Zellerhead actually told you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the next year around I had a good solid year.
[SPEAKER_00]: What happened to you on that road trip?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: The heat and everything else?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I caught up with that heat.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got in shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it's in the Texas League Record Book, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit, I think it was three home runs with the bases loaded, and I hit a double and a triple, and just knocked in a whole slew of runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was 21 runs on two base hits.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this scout, he just couldn't pass that up.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that really saved me there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It gave me the opportunity to go ahead and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as time went on, I got more experience.
[SPEAKER_00]: I began to get a hold of things.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the key to my going back to the Major Leagues was the year I spent with Casey Stingman, 29, actually.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, Casey can really teach you things.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was a great teacher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even though he didn't know how to talk too clearly.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've always said that a fellow that had a career in baseball should have played at least one year for Casey Stingman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the most remarkable character.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to have these meetings in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Honestly, I couldn't keep a straight face.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd hide back in my locker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the funniest man I ever listened to.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did he get his points across?
[SPEAKER_01]: But he'd get them across.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Double talk.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess you knew what he meant.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you think he's put some of that on?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came to the clubhouse one day and got right in the middle of the clubhouse and called a meeting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sat there with a newspaper reading the stock market.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll tell you, fellas.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, this railroad stock is beginning to look pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he said it's going to go up.
[SPEAKER_00]: because the way you fellas are playing, you're really going to be riding the rails pretty soon.
[SPEAKER_00]: He made his point.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to get up in the middle of the clubhouse, right near a trunk and take a fungo bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you know how he could lecture.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he could talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: Every once in a while he'd take a fungo bat and hit the trunk.
[SPEAKER_00]: It sounded like a stick of dynamite going off.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just want to say that any man that played baseball, if he could have one year with Casey Stinger, he was a great manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he did it in such a way that everybody liked him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yet, when he was with the Boston Bees, they were a second division ball club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well.
[SPEAKER_02]: Can you do that much when the material is there?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: We've always said in baseball, you've got to have the horses to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't win unless you do have it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I can see that.
[SPEAKER_00]: mediocre clubs in the early 30s in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the fellas grew up and we got adding stars.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh man, what a ball club we had.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what it takes.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to have enough balance.
[SPEAKER_01]: Down in the street, was Clarence Craft playing that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Clarence Craft, I remember him very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did a lot of home runs, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great favorite in that league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Back in the minor league days then, they had stars that the people just worshipped like they did in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Ziggy Sears in the Texas league, man, he was some man down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went on umpire for many years in the National League.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about that, Toledo, you played in Swainfield?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was that like?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you, I had a short right field fence.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very short.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was tough to pitch in that park.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think the toughest pitcher I ever caught in my whole baseball career was Parmalee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was the wildest.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said he was the only fellow that could pitch one-third of a game under home plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit me all over.
[SPEAKER_00]: I spent an evening with Parmalee.
[SPEAKER_01]: I spent an evening with Parmalee.
[SPEAKER_00]: I
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, it gets you on your arms and around.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he had a tremendous arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: He really threw hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: And where was he going to go?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he hit anybody in the head where they were catching him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: He hit a few people, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: He stood up and hit somebody.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just was no good.
[SPEAKER_01]: They would take him out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He would throw him all over the place.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not that he could before, but he couldn't throw it off.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was on the New York Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and Cliff Melvin and Carl Hubbell
[SPEAKER_00]: They were telling me later that Fitzsimmons used to tell this story.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they'd go in and play a tough series.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd say, all right, Fitz, you pitch, and Hubbell, you pitch, and so on, you pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me pitch that last game.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't want to pitch that first one or two toughies, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he meant it, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come on and smoke them out in that last one.
[SPEAKER_00]: But was LaBarbo with Cleo?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell me about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bebo LaBarbo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's a fascinating name.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good hitter, real good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh, we get the Bebo from him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jigger Stats was playing then, and, uh, oh, heaven, just so many fellas that I've forgotten now, but they had great players then in the minor leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had players coming down from the major leagues, just coming off of their careers up there, and there was a, uh,
[SPEAKER_00]: a pretty high percentage of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, they had so much more minor league ball then.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had like the International League and the American Association, Pacific Coast League, and a lot of good players.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were tough leagues to play in.
[SPEAKER_00]: What were some of the other pitchers with Toledo besides Palmer?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Hugh McQuillin was a pitcher there then, had just come down from the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Palmer Lee, and I wish I could remember a left-hander we had down there was a good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: back so many years now, the names sort of fade from my memory.
[SPEAKER_00]: I get into my old scrapbooks back here once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: That must be fun to look through those.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I kept a scrapbook for years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she has got that thing full of box scores all the way from the Texas League through Where you married then?
[SPEAKER_00]: I married in 27.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she followed you all the way through?
[SPEAKER_00]: All the way in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kept a scrapbook back there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's got
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, if you'd read that scrapbook, you'd have to say, well, I belong in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because the only one she ever put in there was when I had good days.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't put the days in there, but I got the collar.
[SPEAKER_00]: But when I hit a home run or had an outstanding day, knocked in several runs or did something that was worthy of mention in the paper, boy, that went in the scrapbook naturally.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd Toledo do in 29?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too well.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have a very good club.
[SPEAKER_00]: in August and went over to Toronto with Steve O'Neill because they were riding the thick of a pennant fight over there and Toledo had no chance to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Detroit placed me over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it was maybe three weeks to help them out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I joined the club in New York, Detroit, in the fall and stayed all the rest of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you play with Toronto?
[SPEAKER_00]: It doesn't show on the record here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in a few games over there, not too many.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there in the fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: 28, going over there and Steve O'Neill was managing the ball club and we were trying to, they were trying to finish the win but they didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went on to Detroit and I stayed there straight through the end of 38.
[SPEAKER_01]: You went up in September of 29?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your feeling now about going back up?
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd been up a little too soon maybe than you'd gotten your season now.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you feel about going back up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well I felt like I was ready to go back there and play and I had a good solid year and so Bucka Harris just put me right in there and I began catching and of course I caught.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was the first string catcher there in 30, 31, 32, and 33. Who were the other catchers in 29?
[SPEAKER_00]: Marv Shea and Eddie Phillips.
[SPEAKER_00]: But as I went on into 33, you know, I began that streak of airless games in 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I wound up going 100 games and 439 chances out in the air and set an all-time Major League record.
[SPEAKER_00]: Previous record was held by Johnny Bastler, 285 chances.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I figured when I went to 439 and 100 games, I didn't think anybody would break it.
[SPEAKER_00]: There wasn't any time that Buddy Rosar went by me and went about 600 chances.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and it's been broken two or three times since then.
[SPEAKER_00]: But at that time, I put that string together when I was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your gloves weren't as big as they are now, either.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I mean, people need gloves today.
[SPEAKER_01]: How can they get their ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: How can they not catch your stuff?
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got the gloves now that I used.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're downstairs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got them hanging up on the wall down there, the gloves that I used through that stretch, and the one after that in 34 and 35, and the glove I finished up playing with.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Baseball Hall of Fame wanted that glove one time, and I may send it up to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wanted to put it in there and put my record with it because, believe it or not, Ripley had a big cartoon that I have that goes with it, and they wanted to put that on display up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wrote me about it, and I hadn't sent it up, but I think I should send it up there, because although the record is broken since then, at that time it had some interest with all the gloves.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know now how I caught it as well as I did with it when I see the present-day glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's so much improved now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did anybody throw the spitball in your time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you conceal that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit against old Red Faber and John Quinn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they were legal then.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't conceal it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They put it right up here.
[SPEAKER_01]: I meant after it was declared illegal.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, they'd slip them on there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew our guys would slip them on there once in a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you know they were coming?
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, everybody knew that this pitcher, that pitcher would throw some spit and stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd stop and slip a little on there and out of the end.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember one time Bridges loaded one in Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kramer was a hitter and, man, he really loaded up.
[SPEAKER_01]: You feel that spitter down there?
[SPEAKER_00]: I never seen a ball hit so hard in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kramer hung out the clothes in the left center.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was a very effective pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, you know, back in those days with Faber and Mitchell in New York and Quinn and those folks, I think you'd slip Riel and bark then.
[SPEAKER_00]: It grows around you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Man, you chew a piece of that, that's the slickest stuff you ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: But now they're catching on, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: But yeah, I, first game I caught in Philadelphia against John Quinn, I'm darned if I didn't get two for four, and I was strictly a left field hitter, and I hit him between first and second base, hitting that spinner late.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is it that hard to hit, or does it drop so fast, does it?
[SPEAKER_00]: very quick, and most of them are thrown, break down, but Red Faber could break his down or away.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I heard Ty Cobb say one day on a bench in Detroit, Faber was pitching against us, and he says, that is the toughest pitcher that I have ever hit against, was Red Faber.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most difficult for him to hit, because that ball just moved faster than you could adjust anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Same thing with an upper ball, it moves faster than you can adjust to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was on the two clubs where there were knuckleball pitchers, and they are hard to catch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Niggling was one of them, and Top Presnel was the other.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, could they make that ball dance.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, Fitzsimmons threw a knuckle, but they all broke down like a spitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: But these other fellas' knuckles were butterflies, we called them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you had to have the knack of just taking that ball at the very last second.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't go to it and catch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you use a bigger glove in the knuckleball the way they do today?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: We used our same glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I could, by ticking the ball the last second, you could have them well enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they're not easy to catch.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're very difficult to catch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any pick-off plays with runners on the bases?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had our pick-off plays, which we could
[SPEAKER_00]: use our glove to signal, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You would make the signal?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they say first base, you're going to try to get a guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And even first base, it'd come back to me with one if they thought.
[SPEAKER_00]: It always used to go down to field position on O'Greenburg.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of them, all they do is just hold their glove on their knee and take the ball and throw it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That meant you were to throw to them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, you just get a pitch out and throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: But
[SPEAKER_00]: The greatest contest I ever had was with Ben Chapman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd rather steal a bass off of me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I threw him out three times in one game in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: One afternoon, I threw him out twice, tried to steal a third bass, a second bass, and he was a great bass player.
[SPEAKER_00]: So was Case.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't shoot him out if the pitcher didn't help you.
[SPEAKER_00]: If the pitcher had a poor move, good bye.
[SPEAKER_00]: You take a pitcher with a good move, hold him up fairly well, he gets off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me now, you've caught pretty regular up through 33, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they've got Mickey Cochran.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cochran came over there and he was... What did you think about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was right at the height of his career.
[SPEAKER_02]: Here you are, the regular catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here they get somebody who's a...
[SPEAKER_01]: a superstar, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Go ahead, move right in.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was your feeling about that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I felt that he was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was coming in there to manage the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I knew he was going to do a great deal of catching.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I always said to myself, back in those days, I'd rather catch behind Cochran in Detroit and be the first string catcher in St. Louis because I knew they were going to finish last.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd work every day in that hot sun, but it was
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, naturally, I hit better when Cochran came in, because he hit against all the right-handers, and I hit against all the left-handers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I made it, it went up.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 1934, I hit .292, and in 1935, I hit .308.
[SPEAKER_00]: You did play quite a bit then.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have... How many games did you get in in those two years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, around 60, 80 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was thinking Cochran caught the whole... No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: He caught all the World Series in 1935.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 1934, I was in the last game.
[SPEAKER_01]: It must have been an adjustment in your own mental framework, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know you're going to have to kind of take a side.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was in a way.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd love to have continued as a first-string catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, you know, to us then, winning was so doggone important.
[SPEAKER_00]: We wanted to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: We wanted to win pennants.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was right after the Depression.
[SPEAKER_00]: It meant so much to all of us, young, families.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we naturally needed the extra money.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we wanted to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we did.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a lot of prestige to winning.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I wondered about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I looked at the records, saw you playing all this, Nick Cochran comes over, and you're playing so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went in and finished the game the day that Bump Hadley beamed him in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he got a brutal lick in the head.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball sailed.
[SPEAKER_00]: That wasn't a bean ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't throw it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Corcoran said he just strided and the ball was right there and that's the last thing, he lost sight of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just jumped about a foot or two and struck him right over the temple.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there's no way he could avoid it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, Bob Panetta was as sorry as anybody in the world that it happened, but he too didn't have any control over what happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just one of those freak things and that really ended Mike's career right there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was out as manager then, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: the next year around.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very little.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, severe fracture.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just wasn't safe for him to go through the rigors of getting in shape and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bernie Tibbets came on in Detroit and replaced me when I got near the end of my career.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the handwriting's on the wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll explain to you how this happens.
[SPEAKER_00]: You go along and pretty soon you drift back to where you catch it part time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you drift to the bullpen where you catch a game now and then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And simply because if you catch today and again tomorrow, tomorrow you're still tired.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't come back as you get older.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't come back overnight.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember back in the early 30s, I'd catch a doubleheader today and catch one tomorrow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Man, when I got up around 37, 1937, 1938, I'd catch today and I'd begin the show and I'd be tired the next day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's what happens to athletes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although I played until I was, went out in 1945, I stayed in the Major League until I was 41 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I didn't do much playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to ask, are catcher's careers shorter?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there something about the strength and the work that might...
[SPEAKER_00]: I really think catcher's careers are rather long because you're not expected to have great foot speed.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you can throw and receive and hit fairly well, you can have a long career as a catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think, well, it has been the last 15, 20 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: The quickest route to the major leagues is catching.
[SPEAKER_00]: There aren't as many catchers as there are other people playing other positions.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if a fella has pretty good ability, he doesn't want to go back to the play.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'll go to the infield outfield.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'll pitch or first base.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't your knees begin to show after a while, though?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's constant.
[SPEAKER_00]: All the catching I ever did do, I played 20 years of professional baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: My knees never bothered me at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: You just, it's your stamina.
[SPEAKER_00]: You get to where you, as I said a while ago, you don't come back as rapidly.
[SPEAKER_00]: That must happen to fighters and people that just don't, it doesn't come back quick enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I know,
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob Ty Cobb played, you know, he played 23 years, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of fellas, there's no way to determine, I learned this in the scouting field, how long a fella, or how well a fella will wear a baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some wear out at 32, 33 years old, some at 34, 35, most of them 36, 37.
[SPEAKER_00]: A few will go to 40 early on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like Quincy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some of the colored fellows would go longer.
[SPEAKER_00]: They seemed to have great stamina.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there's no way to determine.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember one year in Chicago, we had Ransom Jackson playing there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was a young man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was about 31 or 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all of a sudden, he was through.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just couldn't play anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he just wore out early.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some of the old war horses, they'd go on up there around 39, 40 years old and just keep right on playing.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's no way to determine, really, how well a fellow will wear.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about Harry Heilman and Heinie Minouche.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Minouche with you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about those two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we had Heinie Minouche and Harry Heilman there in 26, Bob Fothergill and Tony Cobb.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you know, that year, that was the most unusual year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fothergill and Minouche
[SPEAKER_00]: and battled each other for the league lead all season.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Manoosh beat him out at the end of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that year, I never have seen since in baseball, all the clubs I was ever with, what a great array of hitters was on that Detroit Tribe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they'd go out and score seven or eight runs, and we didn't have much business.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other clubs scored 10.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I'll tell you that Harmon and Father Gill
[SPEAKER_00]: and Cobb, and throw Garinger in there with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of them I declare that they could really hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd just tear that park apart.
[SPEAKER_00]: But unfortunately then we didn't have the real front line pitching that we needed.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Heilman and Cobb get along?
[SPEAKER_01]: Some kind of feud, I thought, between them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hammond and Cobb got along great.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think Cobb and... Lou Blue hit it off too well.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were different personalities.
[SPEAKER_01]: Blue in the first picture?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was there in that Lou Blue?
[SPEAKER_00]: Lou Blue.
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny Noon came along and replaced him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had old timers in there playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Marty McManus.
[SPEAKER_00]: Marty McManus was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harry Rice.
[SPEAKER_00]: Donny Bush was here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I moved out of there then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jackie Warner was a shortstop there in 26, played most of the games.
[SPEAKER_01]: O'Rourke was one of the old timers, still playing now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was just becoming aware of the game in 29.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was my first game in 29 when the Yankees were playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the players of that year are pretty clear in my mind, but everything before that I had to go back and read about.
[SPEAKER_01]: They don't have quite the realistic image, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have a copy of one of the Who's Who in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first edition was ever printed, about 31 or 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have it in a bookcase down there by my resting chair.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was for a lot of reasons.
[SPEAKER_00]: I get to take a look at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I get the biggest kick out of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see fellas' pictures there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were so young.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most of them had hair.
[SPEAKER_00]: I look at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So many of them are gone now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it's so interesting to me to see how they looked then and the way they are now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're a handsome group.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're a fine looking bunch of men.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I enjoy looking at that book.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I enjoy looking at the encyclopedia.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got, I guess, something next to the last edition.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll pull it down and start coming through that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll run across all the diamonds.
[SPEAKER_00]: All my memories, that brings back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's so many of them in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see how we're doing here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Heine-Mannouche.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that the way that name is pronounced?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Heine-Mannouche.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's his nationality.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I really don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what kind of a guy he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was kind of an unusual name.
[SPEAKER_00]: It sounded German to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: It could have been.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was kind of a chap behind it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a pretty friendly person.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too friendly.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a very determined man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He later left the art club and went to Washington and went to Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah!
[SPEAKER_00]: knock down, drag out series.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had to win it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Selkirk was on second base and somebody got a base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here he comes into the plate and I'm getting the ball about one step down the line towards third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here he comes about that high in the air.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's going to get me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I knew that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was going to have to get him out of there because he meant everything for us to win the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I tagged him out and held onto the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you, he'd pile me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't believe anybody's ever hit harder on the football field than he had been.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just about broke me in half.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he cut you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he didn't jump into me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't stumble with his knees.
[SPEAKER_00]: But in those days, you didn't give an inch.
[SPEAKER_00]: You didn't step up or step back unless the caller got to the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's no way he's going to get there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I guess you see some of it now.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the game's at stake, those catchers don't give a mess.
[SPEAKER_00]: They stay right in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you've got all the best of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got all the gear on you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you're pretty well protected there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Got a lot of scars all over you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, a whole lot of scars.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Texas Leagues put one on my right kneecap, but I'm still carried around.
[SPEAKER_00]: Spike me all the way at the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Other than that, I've got my...
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a real guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Can he play ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Fairly good player.
[SPEAKER_01]: He talked a lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went to Chicago and led the league in talking.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a hilarious fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some kind of a fighter too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to fight some.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to see him a few fights down.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went to Waco, Texas one night.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how about pitching to Ruth?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, some of our fellows handle Ruth pretty good, like Tommy Bridges and Schoolboy Rowe.
[SPEAKER_00]: That type of pitcher could handle him, but the Babe is unpredictable.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he got his pitch, it's goodbye.
[SPEAKER_00]: The thing that was so interesting to me about Ruth as a hitter,
[SPEAKER_00]: He could really hit left-hand pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now Whiteheel, we thought, was one of our better pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've seen him hit Whiteheel just like he owned him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that Whiteheel could break that ball over that curveball, like rolling it off the table.
[SPEAKER_00]: They would step right in there and bang.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could hit it just as good as... How would you call the game for the pitchers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or how would they call it for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: How do you work that out?
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd go with you most of the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Occasionally, you'd have a pitcher out there that he would want to go a certain way with a hitter, or you'd go with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to work with Whitey or Marbury or pitchers like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: There'd be a certain time in the game, you get to a certain situation, and they had in their mind there was a pitch they wanted to throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'd call for the pitch that I thought we should throw, but they'd look me off, and I knew what they were doing, and I'd give them the sign of the other because we wanted to shortstop in second base, but no one was coming.
[SPEAKER_00]: But 90% of the time, the pitchers would go with the catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: They did with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I've always thought it would have been a mistake on my part, or it's a mistake on any catcher's part, to get bullheaded and say, well, you're going to throw this, you're going to throw that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think, at times, a pitcher is more confident in another pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we don't know that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you should go with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, would you go over the pitches before each game?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd sit down with the whole team, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd have a meeting in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most clubs do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know the Brooklyn Club did.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of times in Detroit, especially the first game of a series, you would go down the batting order.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, you'd go over all the hitters on the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so many of them are high ball hitters or low ball hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: What we'd dwell on were the holes you could pitch to.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like a fella might be tight up or down and away.
[SPEAKER_00]: And some fellas are dead fastball hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: Example, Bing Miller was the best curveball hitter of all time.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were unable to throw him a curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd just wire him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we'd pitch him tight, pitch him on his hands.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you watch these fellas play and hit, and you learn where the holes are.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the holes were not very big over top-notch hitters in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to draw that line real fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there's where so many pitchers in the minor leagues had great stuff, but you couldn't pitch in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: They couldn't draw the line fine enough.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because as that hitter goes up, the holes get smaller.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as the pitcher goes up, he can draw the line finer, so everything kind of stays even.
[SPEAKER_00]: But looking at it in another light, if the pitcher
[SPEAKER_00]: control is not fine enough, or the holes on the hitter is too big.
[SPEAKER_00]: Look out, neither one of them is going to stay in the base.
[SPEAKER_00]: The other guy won't let them.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to tell the fellas in the spring when we cut the roster after I got into scouting fields in Florida working with spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd bring a young fella in and say, well look, we're going to have to send you to Montreal, say, or someplace.
[SPEAKER_00]: You need more experience as a hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say, well, what's wrong?
[SPEAKER_00]: I can hit you here just as well as the guys you got out on the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And why can't I stay?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, we don't really decide that.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the fellas on the other clubs that decide it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They won't let you stay up here unless you're ready to stay up here.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very nice way to put it, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the way you do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they begin to see the light and accept it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't blame the other kid.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would stay up there, too, if I could.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a tough thing to tell him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me, what do you talk about when you go out and meet with a pitcher?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you again go out and refresh his memory on how we decided to pitch him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember now, in our meeting, we're going to keep the ball tight on this ball, and we're going to play him to pull, or we'll go away from him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And because your club's going to be playing around that way, we're going to make him hit in the other direction.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you just impress upon them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, you've got to remember to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Concentrate.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to get this guy out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or maybe some situation has developed, which you probably haven't anticipated, and you need some on the spot.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and a lot of times you go out, you can see a fellow that has begun to push the ball, and he's not really slinging the ball good.
[SPEAKER_00]: You go out and say, look, come on now, sling that ball good.
[SPEAKER_00]: You begin to push it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you tell him, because you pitch and run after the pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, sure, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: getting darker tired.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, the manager could see this from the bench, but a lot of times a fellow would, if he's a three-quarter pitcher overhand, he'd begin to drop down a little bit more towards the side of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have to go out there and say, look, get back up over the top.
[SPEAKER_00]: Your ball is flattened out.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not doing anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Get back up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Reach back and get it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And same way with this curveball now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Don't try to overpower it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just put more spin on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It'll break better for you.
[SPEAKER_00]: things like that that you talk to them about.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a lot of times, they get tense up out there, and a little conversation like that breaks the tension, and they settle and come back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that seems really important to our country.
[SPEAKER_01]: Can you tell all the stories about how the catcher goes out and tells you, where are we going to eat dinner tonight?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went out to a pitcher one time, old David's neighbor in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he had sort of been out on the town the night before.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went out to talk to him, and I said, hey,
[SPEAKER_00]: What in the world did you have to drink last night?
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't get near you.
[SPEAKER_00]: He turned around and went back to the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: You really study all the other hitters though, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They show you.
[SPEAKER_00]: You catch against the club two or three times and you begin to learn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you remember the balls that they hit real good and where they were thrown.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you keep a book or just keep it up here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just keep it in your head.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never kept a book, but you remember these guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they're going to beat you at a ball game, you better remember, but be careful that you stay away from their strength and try to stay with their weakness.
[SPEAKER_00]: You never ever hit or never live.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got a weakness somewhere around that strike zone.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you try to distribute it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I mean, one of the smartest positions I think on the team to be a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: It is.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have to know more about what's going on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Know more about what's going on, what your pitcher can do, and watch the players on the infield.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some fellows will drift out of position.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can help in that respect.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that's why catchers like Cochran could probably be managed well as a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't see how somebody like Chris Peeker in center field could be managing the club very well out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: We always felt like a fellow as many and close to the picture of nationally being a catcher himself.
[SPEAKER_00]: I always thought catchers
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a great opportunity to be good managers, but if they could handle me.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the main thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you the year I managed Mr. Rickey's club in Fort Worth, I had a bunch of young kids just back from the war, and man, they wanted to play, and they had great ability.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I started to have meetings at the clubhouse, and I never had so many questions thrown at me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I told them at the outset, and I looked.
[SPEAKER_00]: If there's anything you don't understand about this game and you want to know, you ask me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because if I don't know the answer, I'll sure get it for you."
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I can get it from Mr. Rickey.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's one of the smartest men the game has ever known.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, he analyzed everything and knew so well about every phase of the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to go down to spring training and he'd have all the managers in the front row.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everyone would have a meeting for an hour.
[SPEAKER_00]: put all the players in the background.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd start out, maybe let's just name a few, he'd start out with hitting, bunting, catching, first base, second base, shortstop, third base, doing a course of spring training, cover every position, and tell every one of them how it should be played.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he'd go into, he wanted all the players to hear this, but then he'd talk to the manager and say,
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's the situation.
[SPEAKER_00]: When are you going to play the infield end?
[SPEAKER_00]: When are you going to play it back?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had the answers for all this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was good sound baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd give us all this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in the summer, he'd come and watch us play.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you'd better remember what he said and not play your infield ends the wrong time and play it back and so forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it was a great education, I'll tell you, of all the years I ever played professional ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I got back into managing, I learned a great deal about baseball then that I didn't really get into too deep when I was playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wish I had.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wish I had this training.
[SPEAKER_00]: I might have been able to contribute more.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he had a great system.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why he was so successful with all of his clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: His players were, you look at that Dodger club.
[SPEAKER_00]: to stay there so well at school.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there's a way to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a way to play every position and a way to pitch and a way to hit and bunt and all that sort of thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Baseball gets to be a vast field of things that you need to know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have a set of lectures here that were put together back in the early 50s when they had these coaches clinics all over the country.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the National Association gave us permission to hand them out in coach meetings after I went to Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's a great set of lectures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most of them are 30 minutes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of them are 45.
[SPEAKER_00]: It covers every phase of the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we'd give them out to college coaches, high school coaches.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who delivered the lectures?
[SPEAKER_00]: we were appointed.
[SPEAKER_00]: In North Carolina, every year Mace Brown and I would do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd cover pitching and I'd cover catching and offensive and defensive plays.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the greatest thing that was ever put together.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this was put together by 15 or 20 of baseball's top players, like shortstop, second baseman, center fielder, catcher, first baseman,
[SPEAKER_00]: And all by managers on percentage play and how to play your club and how to have spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: All these things, all in this set election, the finest thing I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we used them for years and years and give them out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess they still do.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what they do today.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been away from the game five years and I retired at the end of
[SPEAKER_00]: I retired at age 68, 1972.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had done so much special assignment scouting after I was director of scouting in Chicago and Milwaukee and Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went back into special assignment scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tell you, I was just flying all over the country for several years.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next day I'd be here, and the next day in San Antonio, the next day in Los Angeles, the next day maybe in Spokane, wherever the top prospects were.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't travel like that when you were in the minors, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was train travel like in those early days?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you, we rode trains on for years after I was in the Major Leagues, a long time before we began flying.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all my career was on trains.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do on the train?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was just a group of fellas that all the
[SPEAKER_00]: regular players were in the, what we called, number one car, and we always called number two the riffraff.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they put the secondary players and pitchers back there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And guys played a lot there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were like a bunch of kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had a good time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They told me I went to the Texas League, would ride all night in the doggone trains with the windows up, didn't have any air conditioning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hot as whiz.
[SPEAKER_00]: First thing he told me, he said, don't sleep over near the window.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, those mosquitoes will ram their bills right through there and get you right through the screen.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, uh, uh.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know how you could sleep in that situation.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I didn't sleep much.
[SPEAKER_00]: You just rested a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: You really couldn't sleep because, uh, it was so hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: And later on, they began to come over with some air conditioning, but.
[SPEAKER_00]: Leaving in the hotel room, it's been pretty hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, it was hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: Down at the Rice Hotel in Houston, we'd go in there in the Texas League, we'd go up to bed, we'd wet the sheet, and pull the bed out and have big ceiling fans right under the fan, wet that sheet, and we'd be pretty comfortable.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the most air-conditioned we could get a hold of in those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: But... What about playing on a hot Sunday afternoon in Houston?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, sweet boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Way cold.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Waco had an oil infield.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't stand still.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've seen the infield just stand out there like a prancing horse.
[SPEAKER_01]: They pour water in the shoes.
[SPEAKER_00]: The field was so hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they pour water in the shoes between innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Actually, pour it right in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was so hot you could feel the spikes under there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Would anybody pass out?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you'd get in shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could get yourself conditioned to that hot weather.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd go out and play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it was hot, but... Did you ever catch a doubleheader in that kind of heat?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How much weight did you lose?
[SPEAKER_01]: About eight, nine pounds, somewhere in that area in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they have salt pills?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, but you'd gain it back by the next day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lose it again.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ty Cobb used to have a mix that he had put together.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd play in Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was awfully hot in Washington, especially with the rain in the morning and the clear off in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd take a, have the trainer take a sack, fill it full of oatmeal, and put it in a bucket of ice water, and cut up a lot of lemons and oranges and put them in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you'd drink that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the most healthful drink you ever tasted.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it would strengthen you.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wouldn't make you sick like if you were to drink ice water.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a lot of used that back in the day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now these players today, when they're fishing airplanes,
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know what it was, but it's so much nicer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know when I got into scouting, I traveled a lot with the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Chicago 13 years, Mr. Wrigley, in scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I did director scouting there.
[SPEAKER_00]: What years were those with the Cubs?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there in, let's see, 47 to the end of 59.
[SPEAKER_00]: I scouted there, did all special assignment scouting all the time I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And until the last year I was director of scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went to Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And see, I spent nine years with Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: 60 to 60 through 68.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Milwaukee in the, well, the fall of, was there 60?
[SPEAKER_00]: through, let me figure it out now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there five years in Milwaukee, went to Atlanta, and stayed on there until the end of 70.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went to Montreal in 71, 72, 73.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, all my people moved from Atlanta to Montreal.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went on up there with John McHale and scouted three more years of Special Assignments
[SPEAKER_00]: But I was director of scouting all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Milwaukee from 1960 through 1966.
[SPEAKER_01]: And down to Atlanta, too, when you went to Atlanta?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I went to Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remained director of scouting through 1966, 1967, 1968, 1969.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did special assignment scouting in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Jim Fanning took my place there as Director of Scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I moved from there to Montreal, continued in Special Assignment Scouting until I retired at the end of 72.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, now getting back earlier here, you mentioned earlier in the Texas League you didn't have night ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: You played in the hot afternoons.
[SPEAKER_01]: When did you first play night ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: First night game I would play, it was in Cincinnati after I'd gone to Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have any night ball ahead of that, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were just bringing it in to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you were in the Big Lakes from then on.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess they went into the minors in about 30 or so, first night ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the first night game I think was played out in Des Moines.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I never did play in a night game until I actually went to the Cincinnati Park one night and played the first night game.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next big game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was a regular league game.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was... Oh, when you were with...
[SPEAKER_01]: I was with Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me finish off your career here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Detroit, you were from through 38?
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Brooklyn in the latter part of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd say along about first of September.
[SPEAKER_01]: About 38?
[SPEAKER_00]: 38.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, how long were you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Brooklyn in 39.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was traded to New York for Jimmy Ripple in the fall of 39.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was in New York all of 40.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't play any, but I was a bullpen coach and was an active player on the club, although I didn't play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the catcher, Harry Danning?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Babe Phelps, Harry Danning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Danning was the catcher in New York, and Ken O'Day.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then I was released by New York at the end of the 1940 season, and I went to Milwaukee with Bill Killefer.
[SPEAKER_00]: and was made a free agent, and I signed with the St. Louis Browns in the spring of 42.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were with Milwaukee 41?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 42, I went to spring training with the St. Louis Browns.
[SPEAKER_00]: I stayed on with them until about the 1st of May, and I was released and signed by the St. Louis Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I stayed there on the Cardinal Club, I guess for about, I'd say six weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Mr. Rickey wanted me to go over and take over the Rochester Club and manage it for the rest of the years, playing manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which I did because Crabtree was a manager and he had, he took sick and he couldn't manage so he had to drop out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And through the winter,
[SPEAKER_00]: Then of 42, Mr. Rickley, Mr. Rickey went to Brooklyn at that time from St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he immediately took me to Brooklyn with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I stayed in Brooklyn as an active player due to wartime years, 43, 44, and back in 45 until July of 45.
[SPEAKER_00]: put Sukuth and I off of the active list, and we began scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when we scouted.
[SPEAKER_00]: I helped scout all the colored clubs at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got Newcomb, Campanella, and all those fellas.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when we scouted.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when those fellas came on.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he put Sukuth and I with George Sisler and Wynne Matthews.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's where we began learning about scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I continued in scouting until my brief periods of managing in 46 and 47.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I continued on in scouting until I retired.
[SPEAKER_00]: 46 and 47 Fort Worth, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 46 in Fort Worth and 47 in Macon, Georgia.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I went with the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Chicago Cubs, Jack Shinn.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I managed there, and at the end of the year, I went on their scouting staff.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did you feel about scouting for these black players?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you that was an experience.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd go to New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: They played a doubleheader every Sunday, but they had four colored clubs playing in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we got to see so many more players every Sunday afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd play one week in the Yankee Stadium and the next week in Polo Ground, because one of the other clubs would be out of town.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Sessler and Sookie and Matthews and I, we'd all go over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was an experience to see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, it was attended by mostly colored people.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they danced up and down the aisles and threw stuff and bet money.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had great players on the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Look at the players we were looking at.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I remember old Josh Gibson in a game in the Yankee Stadium one Sunday afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit a ball, I believe, to right field in his right-hand interval as far as Ruth would ever hit one.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a powerhouse hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got to see so many of the colored players that came on and made their way big in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a free and open market then.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was up for grabs.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Mr. Rickey got in on the ground floor and scouted these players.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he got to Campanella, Jackie Robertson and Milcom just got top players in the colored field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were young then, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he did extensive scouting, and he scouted colored players all down in Mexico and everywhere then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever think much about this when you were playing ball back in the 30s and 20s, about the fact that there were no blacks in it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not a one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never played against a colored player in my baseball career.
[SPEAKER_00]: came on after I finished and got into the scouting field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I really scouted colored players from then on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did this special assignment on Ernie Banks and we bought Ernie Banks from the Kansas City Monarchs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was put on him by Whit Matthews.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in Chicago and he called me in the office one morning and said, Ray, I want you to fly off to Davenport, Iowa and see a young colored shortstop that we just had a call about.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, the business manager down in Macon saw that Kansas City Monarch Club play there last night, and the business manager's name was Gordon.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, somebody ought to see Banks.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a fine-looking young ballplayer.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I immediately went out to Davenport and picked him up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that night, Buck O'Neill was the manager of the Monarchs at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I watched Banks play and take in the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: I called Buck O'Neill over and I told him who I was and I said, tell me something about this kid Banks.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well I'll tell you, he's a fine boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd just come back from the service and he said he has good ability.
[SPEAKER_00]: So through us scouting and reporting and buying banks, it brought Buck O'Neill in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bet you he stayed there 20 years scouting, just through banks.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I still have my original report right here now, my file that I made on banks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we bought banks for $21,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: And about two or three years later, St. Louis offered Mr. Wrigley $500,000 for banks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Mr. Wrigley says, I don't want $500,000 for banks.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just want another bank.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's not for sale.
[SPEAKER_00]: And yeah, we went on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I followed him on to Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_00]: and into Chicago and had the Negro American League Color World Series and they played in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I met with Matthews at the White Sox Park that afternoon.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, what about Banks?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, get him, get him somewhere other.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the next morning I had a meeting with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I told Cabaretta, the manager at that time, I said, this boy is not too far away from playing in Chicago right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And sure enough, the next year he played in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he have a good night that you saw him have the first night?
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit one in Davenport, over the fence, and there's a water tank way out there in the woods.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the last time I saw that ball, he was going by that water tank.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, that's enough for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he's hit a ball that far one time, he can do it again.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was a great player.
[SPEAKER_00]: And a splendid fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought that was one of my
[SPEAKER_00]: top people that I ever signed.
[SPEAKER_00]: I flew out to the coast one year and signed Dick Ellsworth.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I'm playing a high school game.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got him and numerous other players that I was involved in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Too many to mention that we were signing in Detroit, I mean in Milwaukee and Atlanta when I was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about, though back in the 20s if there is in your playing career,
[SPEAKER_01]: And there were no blacks playing ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did this occur to you fellows much who seemed... why they weren't there?
[SPEAKER_01]: You probably didn't think about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we knew there were some great players around.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because some of the boys would tell me of playing in exhibition games in the fall against them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Tommy Bridges told me one time, he said, man, they really got some players.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they just hadn't broken the line to bring them into the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a pity, too, because there were a lot of great
[SPEAKER_00]: Colored players all along, even back before my time, they were great colored players.
[SPEAKER_00]: They just didn't recognize them and bring them into the game, which they should have done.
[SPEAKER_01]: There had been too much feeling against it, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, there would have been then.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it was quite a daring thing for Ricky himself to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when he did, I guess there was some opposition to bringing Robinson in.
[SPEAKER_01]: A great deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: A great deal at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the thing that hurt me more about the colored situation in baseball after I was in the scouting
[SPEAKER_00]: and traveling around, in Milwaukee for an example.
[SPEAKER_00]: Even as late as that has been, our club would go down to Houston and Aaron couldn't stay at the same hotel with us, he'd have to stay out of town someplace.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd see these young colored players down like in Blackwell, Oklahoma or someplace that we owned, that we'd signed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they couldn't go into a restaurant and they had to stay out places.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it just didn't seem like people ought to be treated that way to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was happy to see it change around and bring them in and give them the same accommodations that all the rest of the players were getting.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were only right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess Robinson really had to put up with a lot at first.
[SPEAKER_01]: He sure did.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Rickey must have known his man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had great desire and had great ability and carried him over these rough spots and he just didn't let anything stop him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he went right ahead and went about the business of playing baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, now here's something I like to ask old players.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you get along with umpires?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you, I got along pretty well with umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had my usual, a few run-ins with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me tell you a little incident that happened in Detroit one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Dineen was the umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were going to have an off day, and we were playing that afternoon, and I heard the umpires talking.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said, well, what we'll do tomorrow, let's just take a little trip over to Windsor, visit around over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you know, back in those days, it was dry in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't get beer or anything you wanted over in Canada.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the next day was an off day.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next day around,
[SPEAKER_00]: Deneen was umpiring back of the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I thought he missed a strike or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't turn around, I just backed up along the side of him and I said, you fellas must have got ahold of some bad stuff over in Canada yesterday.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, that's all for you, get out of here.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, you know, he probably didn't, but I just, it's the meanest thing I could think of to say to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, get out of here, you're through.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Bucky Harris
[SPEAKER_00]: bounced off the bench and started to play, and he says, what in the world are you throwing Ray out of the game for?
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, and you go with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's truly about to.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I really touched a nerve with him there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know to this day if the man ever had a bottle of beer or not, but I just couldn't think of anything else mean to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another time I had to run in with the umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was having a real bad night.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I backed up alongside of him and I said, you sure you feel all right?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, yes, I do.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, you just can't be that lousy and feel all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, you've got to be sick.
[SPEAKER_00]: Get out of here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who is that?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a fellow down at Bacon, Georgia one night.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if he remembers his name now, but I'll tell you right now, when I told him that, I knew I was going to get the rest of the night off.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was a good line, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Too good to waste.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I have gotten after umpires on those hot days.
[SPEAKER_00]: And right away, they sense it, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're irritable, and you think they missed a strike or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they say, you can talk all you want to, but you're not going to be thrown out of this game.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're going to stay here and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're not going to get out of here on this hot day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that hurt me, too, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to do something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean... Would you actually try to get thrown out sometimes?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just say these mean things to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought they were mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe they'd do a little better or bear down harder.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know now that when I sit here and talk that they were doing the best they could.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty tough job.
[SPEAKER_00]: It is a tough job.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's so many of those balls in the pits that are just right there on the corner that could be called either way.
[SPEAKER_00]: How can you tell if a ball is a sixteenth of an inch off of the plate or on the plate?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a matter of seeing and judgment that you do these things.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think the umpire does.
[SPEAKER_00]: I really admire umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it's a tough profession, but somebody must do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And these fellows have got the training, and I think overall they do a wonderful job.
[SPEAKER_01]: You think, say you've got a batter up there who has a reputation for a very good eye, and he takes a pitch right on the outside corner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there a tendency you think the umpire might give him that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I think some of the little top hitters, they didn't seem to call him quite as, I don't think they called some of those fine liners as much as they did all day.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like Ty Cobb, who had such a good eye.
[SPEAKER_01]: He probably got a few breaks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted Williams had one of the greatest eyes at the plate of anybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could just take a ball, he wouldn't even offer it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just barely missed that plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: I couldn't do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe it did miss the plate, but the umpire said it didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: If it was that close, I'd either swing or be called out, but he wouldn't even offer the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd just look at that ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great eyesight, man.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's really such a great hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do any umpires stand out as being a little bit better?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, there were so many good umpires over the years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or worse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, there were some that maybe didn't rate as high as the others, but I'll tell you, there were some of those fellows that were really good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I always admired Cal Hubbard.
[SPEAKER_00]: One time, Lou Kline told me that the thing that hurt him so much in baseball is that he'd hit a ground ball down at the infield, and he'd run his tail off the first base and just get nicked.
[SPEAKER_00]: and said, instead of the umpire calling him out like they do today, he said, old Cal was standing down there with his hands in his vest and said, as he'd go by and take a look at it, he said, all he'd give him was just his thumb, like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just that little thumb.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, one day he turned around to him and he said, can't you give me a better out than that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Lou Kline?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: The infielder with the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was later with the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, can't you give me a better out than that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Not many people argue with Cowley.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not many.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill McGowan?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I like Bill.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember him in 34 and 5.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, McGowan was a good umpire.
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy Evans?
[SPEAKER_01]: Billy Evans was a great umpire.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he in business when you were growing up?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he was still umpiring.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of those fellas back there were real good umpires.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was it like in the World Series?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, believe it or not, World Series, you can play it for years and years.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just something about a World Series that's a little different.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, you get up to it more.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's more excitement.
[SPEAKER_00]: The idea of World Series, it is, it's different playing a regular season.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's something about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all the players feel a sense that it's extra special when you're in a World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you didn't catch it either once?
[SPEAKER_00]: I finished up the last game of the 34 series.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Caulkin caught all the 35 series, because he won six games, and we won over the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had a great series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's too bad you couldn't have gotten in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well.
[SPEAKER_01]: And as you say, you're on a championship team, so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great to win, I'll tell you.
[SPEAKER_00]: People have said so many times over the years,
[SPEAKER_00]: Why didn't you complain?
[SPEAKER_00]: Why didn't you get them to trade you and all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Like I said earlier in our talks, that I'd rather have been there and been second string than have been first string in some place where I'd worked myself to death and wouldn't have reaped the harvest that I did reap, money-wise, from being in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that team have, say, 34?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there a leader on the field other than Cochran?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Cochran was really our leader, but we had men on there like Gaussman and Gerringer and... Billy Rogel, would he be a leader type?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not as much as some of the other fellas.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have to think that Cochran...
[SPEAKER_00]: I wouldn't think Gerringer, he's so quiet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gerringer's quiet, but he did so many things so well, so easy that everybody was kind of... Well, it followed him, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, our holler guys were Gerald Walker and fellows like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was something.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he really swallow a bug in the back of trying to steal second base one time?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever hear that story?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jojo White one day, they had a close play at the plate, and he's sitting there, and he said he just placed his finger in his nose, and when he said, slide, he said he almost ratted his finger out the top of his head.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Gerald swallowed his tobacco one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was a wild kind of a bass rocker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Unpredictable.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stole a lot of basses, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he on his own, still?
[SPEAKER_00]: He might as well have been.
[SPEAKER_01]: He took everything in his own hands.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to drive a car crazy, but he still had so much ability that he offset a lot of his mistakes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harvey Walker was up, too, for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he was there a while, and he left.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't stay too long.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was not quite the player that his brother was.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Roy Johnson?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he still with you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, we were with Roy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Roy was there and played quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was sort of a temperamental type player.
[SPEAKER_00]: Still, he had good ability.
[SPEAKER_00]: But what about Billy Rogel?
[SPEAKER_00]: Billy was a good, steady shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the kind of fellow that Cochran would pride him a little bit every once in a while and keep him on his toe and keep him going.
[SPEAKER_00]: He always had that plug at the back in his mind, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good playmaker.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could really handle that glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: Covered a lot of ground and teamed with Garinger.
[SPEAKER_00]: They made a great combination of second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Marv Owen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Marv Owen.
[SPEAKER_00]: We used to call him Shovelhands.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shovelhands.
[SPEAKER_00]: No matter what went down there, he scooped it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was like this.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a head and a little bigger butt.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was a sure-handed third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't get beat up all over.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd just catch it and throw him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you know, in the 35 series, when Greenberg got that fractured wrist, he moved right over to first base and did a whale of a job at first base and moved Fleet Clifton off the bench at third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got hit right here and fractured a bone in his elbow, in his wrist.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had Owen played first base before?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he had earlier in his career.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hadn't played in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: He moved over there and he had such good hands, he played well over first base for us.
[SPEAKER_00]: But our clubs then had great depth.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had good bench strength.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Goose Gatlin.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember that Goose's base hit in that 35th series.
[SPEAKER_00]: We saw Texas League signals right over second base that scored Cochran for the winning run in that sixth game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Man, I'd never seen a town go so wild.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was about tore down the ballpark in downtown, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a great celebration for them to win that thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said it was a bigger celebration for them.
[SPEAKER_00]: World War I ended.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he a very talkative chap, the goose?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, ordinary.
[SPEAKER_00]: He, I mean, he's not overly talkative.
[SPEAKER_00]: Goose is a very likable fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: He, uh...
[SPEAKER_00]: He, uh... Great admirer of my boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: My kids were young.
[SPEAKER_00]: They loved Goose.
[SPEAKER_00]: They just thought he was great.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could sure hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: he really could hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me, did you ever catch a no-hitter?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I caught a perfect game one time, oh yes, but I never caught a, eventually I didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught the game in Detroit that Tommy Bridges pitched against Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went down to the ninth inning with two men out, and he had a perfect game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hadn't walked a guy, didn't have a base hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Walter Johnson was managing the Washington Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he brought in Dave Harris to pinch hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: With Judge, Joe Judge sitting on the bench and I believe Sam Rice both.
[SPEAKER_00]: And both of them left handed.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he put him up to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tommy threw him a high fastball.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was about there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was not even the strike zone.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he broke his back.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had his left heel pervasive.
[SPEAKER_01]: And spoiled that perfect game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think he brought in Harris just to
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, but Johnson sent him in there, which, ordinarily, you'd say, well, this is great.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he just took a wild swing at that first pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why he didn't send in Rice or Judge, because he wanted him to get the no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Harris was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he took a wild swing at this high fastball, and darned if he didn't break his head.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sounded like an experience.
[SPEAKER_00]: Get it in the field for a base hit, and just everybody died with it, because he was so close to a perfect game.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they didn't make it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get the next minute?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you did catch a no-hitter in the minors, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where was this?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think someplace I caught a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was when I was with the Toledo Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: It seemed like somebody pitched a no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I never caught one in a major league.
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught several one-hitters and two-hitters, but not another no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I called no hitter, I believe I would have remembered it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the easiest pitchers to catch at Detroit?
[SPEAKER_00]: Like Bridges?
[SPEAKER_00]: Crowder was very easy to catch.
[SPEAKER_00]: None of them are really difficult now at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: I feel like they were.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you, did you catch any of those games at Rose, Winning Street there in 34?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was remarkable.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know one year we finished the season in Detroit, and Johnny Allen had won.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had tied the all-time record.
[SPEAKER_00]: But out that day, and we just figured out Allen had beat us, I caught the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they pitched, Bucky Harris pitched Jake Wade.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wasn't even a regular pitcher on our staff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wow!
[SPEAKER_00]: Always wild.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went out that day and was darned if he didn't beat John Allen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well that day Jake pitched a masterpiece and he beat Allen one to nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Broke his streak.
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept him from breaking the record.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's another little incident I'd like to tell you about.
[SPEAKER_00]: visiting with Charlie Garington, his wife, down in West Palm Beach one spring.
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife and I ran into him one afternoon and we got talking and Charlie and Marv Owen were all his great friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Charlie said that they had their, had a wedding anniversary and they got this very heavy package from Marv Owen and said when they opened it
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a brick out of the church that Charlie and his wife, of course, were married in out in California.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Marv Owen was their best man.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he went by this church one day and they were tearing it down, so he just went over and got a brick out of it and sent it to Charlie.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they got the brick down.
[SPEAKER_00]: They think it was the greatest thing ever happened for him to send a brick out of that church.
[SPEAKER_00]: One year I was a scout for Detroit and they called him into Detroit in the fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he came on from California with not many clothes on.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were in his suitcase and he got out there and he was about to freeze.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Carrington loaned him his overcoat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was the nicest, warmest overcoat.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he just wore it around there and wore it back home.
[SPEAKER_00]: I called Charlie one day and he said, Charlie, I want to send your coat back to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie said, forget it, keep it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a present for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I was thinking about these stories they tell about Hogson and Gerringer who didn't talk much and they roomed together and they'd get up in the morning and say good morning and say good night at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: How true are those kind of stories?
[SPEAKER_00]: They're pretty much true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Neither one of them talked much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Charlie, Charlie had never talked much around in groups, but you could sit down and talk to him casually.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very easy to visit with and a very likable fellow to talk to.
[SPEAKER_00]: I enjoyed talking to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it all cut out a little effort, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: You meet these fellas along the way and some of them things stand out in your mind that you remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about your biggest thrill in baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Has anything stand out to you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe down in the Texas league, that hot streak you had.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a hot streak.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think probably one of the greatest thrills I ever had in baseball was breaking that record.
[SPEAKER_00]: And for a real thrill was the day that Gosling got his base hit and we won the 35 World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: We wanted to win so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: We lost the year before to the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Deans beat us two games apiece in the 34 series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Knocked us out of getting the World Series ring.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the next year around, we won that World Series ring.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was just a great thrill to win it, knowing that we were going to get it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a crowning thing for us.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that, among many other nice gifts that we got.
[SPEAKER_00]: You bought some property out here too, I understand.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's the thing on my desk you might like to see.
[SPEAKER_00]: This very beautiful thing was given to us in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kind of a plaque.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I have in that drawer there my lifetime pass in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: You might want to see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know you've seen them before.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let me just hand this out to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here it is.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was awfully proud to get that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that 34 series, though, was that when they started throwing the stuff at Medrick?
[SPEAKER_00]: Medrick slid into Marvel and Third Base and upended him, and the fans were so disturbed about it, they wouldn't let Medrick come back to left field.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they threw, I don't know where they got all the vegetables and oranges and apples and things from.
[SPEAKER_00]: They came ready, anyhow.
[SPEAKER_00]: They covered the field with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Judge Landis, of course, called Medrick over and asked him some questions and, of course, banished him from the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had to put in somebody from Medrick to finish the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was a double dose of bad feeling because
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody knew the Cardinals already had us beat that day when this thing happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lopsided score.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they went down to the final game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you in that game?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, at the end.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fresh beat us at ballgame that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he hit a double or triple down the right field line off of Auker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Really broke the game open.
[SPEAKER_01]: Helman Auker, there's a name we haven't mentioned.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Auker, I caught the pennant winning game in 1935.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were playing the Browns in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Auker beat them 2 to 1 to clinch the pennant.
[SPEAKER_00]: Auker was a, he and Hogshead were identical on the one with the right hand and one with the left hand.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were underhand pitchers and threw sinkers all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Threw climbing curveballs and they were really tough pitchers to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: kind of tough to catch, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it was tough to catch.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we were fortunate to have him on our side, both of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were good men, good pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: That offer really went way down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was due to a football injury.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great football player.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great college player in football out in the University of Kansas.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had a shoulder injury, and then
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was a pitcher, of course, at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he had to go down and throw underhanded.
[SPEAKER_00]: And from that time on, he became an outstanding underhanded pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: He couldn't raise his arm up, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: It didn't affect his velocity or control.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come under there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, Hogs would come under there, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know that about Hogs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they always would love to have
[SPEAKER_00]: came across a young prospect somewhere in my scouting experience that flew like that, underhand.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody was down under.
[SPEAKER_00]: All on top, three-quarters now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there any feeling about Hogshead or any discrimination because he was an Indian?
[SPEAKER_01]: None at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was a very likable fellow in our club.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a good sense of humor.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't one of those staid sort of individuals that was an Indian chief or anything, just a regular fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was Art Herring with the team?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Art pitched there for a few years.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lives out in, I think it's someplace in Indiana.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to stop and see him, but I haven't been able to yet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I'd like to see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: across paths with some of these fellas, but... Well, you must have run into a few of them while you were scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And fellas are former players in the scouting field.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been seeing a lot of those fellas around.
[SPEAKER_00]: They come around here sometimes.
[SPEAKER_00]: We have several Major League Scouts in this area here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gil English, of course, is retired now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's scouted for many, many years.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Milwaukee and the Giants, the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Mace Brown, he still is active with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Billy Smith has scouted for us for our organization a long time in Milwaukee.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's now with Houston, been down there for about 10 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: He lives right here, about four or five miles from here.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, we have about half a dozen fellas right around here that some of them are retired, some of them are still active, but they're all my golfing buddies.
[SPEAKER_01]: We all go out there and play golf.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you scout college games?
[SPEAKER_00]: They do, my brother and all.
[SPEAKER_00]: They scout high school, college, legion.
[SPEAKER_01]: We have a pretty good college team up where I am.
[SPEAKER_01]: We've gone quite far in the Division III of the NCAA for a couple years.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, we have the World Series, I think, called the National Championship for Division III, the smallest school in Marietta.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that draws quite a few scouts up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mentioned, I asked you just when we snapped the other tape, Bob, about batting against Walter Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I remember hitting against Walter Johnson very distinctly.
[SPEAKER_00]: I should have because I'd heard so much about him as a kid growing up and how hard he could throw and all.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a great kick out of hitting against him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you a little story about him you might want to hear.
[SPEAKER_00]: One day Whitlow Watt and I were sitting on the bench in Detroit
[SPEAKER_00]: This is back in the early 30s.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Walter Johnson came out through our dugout, as players did then, and he stopped to talk a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the manager for Washington?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we said, Walter, back in your heyday, when you first came up to the Major Leagues, we're just wondering, how hard could you throw?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he said, boys, I could throw just as hard as I wanted.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, if I wanted to really reach back and get it, I could just throw as hard as, meaning that if he had to get a follow out, he'd just strike him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, back in those days when Washington was finishing last every year, he'd win 20, 25 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I believe what he said, because at that time, we'd sit on the bench and watch him pitch batting practice against his own club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we all agreed that he could throw harder than anybody else.
[SPEAKER_01]: His pitching staff said that he was already through as a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was a big sidewinder down here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He must have never had an arm problem.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never got tired.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could throw hard even long towards the end of his career when I had a chance to hit against him a couple of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you get a hit?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit two balls pretty good off of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember getting a hit off of him, but if you ask me about Bob Feller, I can remember the hits I got off of him, but not too many.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think Bob Feller was the toughest pitcher I ever faced in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was so difficult to follow.
[SPEAKER_00]: All his motions.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, his whole delivery was back of him, and it wasn't bothering me so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a great curveball, he could throw hard, but he pitched all the time looking out in the right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, if you just look around at me, that worried me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was afraid you were going to lose sight of me at the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Ty Cobb batted for you though once.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we were playing a game in Detroit, and I had faced Johnson once or twice.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got in a situation where there were a couple men on, so Cobb pinch hit for me and hit a double.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember that very distinctly.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't feel bad about that at all, as I said earlier.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was a great thrill to hit against a pitcher so great as Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, this has been a lot of fun, and I sure enjoyed it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just wish I could stay more.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it's a real pleasure just to sit down and reminisce here and hit some of the highlights over all these years.
[SPEAKER_01]: You've had such a career, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm sure you've left out an awful lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, heavens, I can't.
[SPEAKER_01]: The tape is so short.
[SPEAKER_00]: It'd take a lot of sessions to catch up on that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish sometime that you could see the scrapbooks and the pictures and things that are here.
[SPEAKER_00]: My grandsons now keep asking me, he says, Papa, why don't you make a Hall of Fame, put all your pictures right up on the wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, maybe we'll do it someday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that'd be great.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It is now about
[SPEAKER_02]: almost three weeks later from the time this tape was recorded.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was at High Point, North Carolina in Ray Hayworth's home on Monday, March 13, 1978.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm now back here at home where I've been for quite a while, and it's Friday evening, March 31, 1978.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't have a chance to
[SPEAKER_02]: comment on the tape at the time, and I forgot about it when we got back here and had other things to do.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I don't have anything to do now.
[SPEAKER_02]: I do have a few things, but I thought I'd get a little bit down on this tape here about Ray Hayworth.
[SPEAKER_02]: As I recall it, I left Ernie Shore's home around one o'clock or so.
[SPEAKER_02]: And trying to get out of Winston-Salem, I got lost.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't really get lost.
[SPEAKER_02]: I did make one or two wrong turns.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I finally made it out of town there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the high point is only about 15 or 20 miles away on the road south.
[SPEAKER_02]: little southeast of Winston-Salem, so I drove down there, and I knew that the road from my conversation the day before with Ray Hayworth, when I set up the interview, I knew that the road off of the main road out to his home was north of town several miles, so I kept my eye open for roads leading off to the left as I drove down, but I
[SPEAKER_02]: Finally got into High Point in the outskirts, and I drove into a service station.
[SPEAKER_02]: Asked where this one road was.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've forgotten now the name of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they said it was back about half a mile, so I hadn't really gone too far in.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I worked my way back and then out this road several miles.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I came to Westminster Village, which I think that's some pretty good recaller, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think Westminster Village is the name of the little development where he is located.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I found the road.
[SPEAKER_02]: that he mentioned and weave my way around.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a very sparsely populated area, a few farmhouses scattered about, very nicely maintained.
[SPEAKER_02]: As I pulled into the driveway here, there was an old gentleman out working in a wood pile and getting some things organized.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know if that was Ray Hayworth or not.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I pulled into the parking space there and he came over and piled his wood up and then came to me
[SPEAKER_02]: Greeted me as Mr. Murdock, and I greeted him as Ray Hayworth.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he was the right party.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very congenial and friendly.
[SPEAKER_02]: A pretty big man, although as a player he didn't strike me as very big.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was rather lanky and lean.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he's somewhat lanky and not so lean now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Probably about six feet and filled out quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's 73 years old, remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: But ruddy complexion, full face, a couple of chins, which he never had as a ball player.
[SPEAKER_02]: But good health and robust.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he works outdoors a great deal.
[SPEAKER_02]: We chatted briefly out in the driveway.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he, at that time, mentioned about some of this land he had inherited and quite a bit more he had purchased with his 1934 World Series check.
[SPEAKER_02]: that his son is a public official in High Point, something to do with subdivisions, when property is subdivided and sold.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so with his son's assistance, he worked out some plan by which much of this land was divided and sold.
[SPEAKER_02]: So they've made money, all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: The house is a beautiful house.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they have nice things.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he's a man of considerable wealth based on land.
[SPEAKER_02]: and the selling of some of this land.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we went in the house.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had to change his boots.
[SPEAKER_02]: He didn't want to track his muddy boots all over the house, so he changed them.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then we went into the living room.
[SPEAKER_02]: I met his wife, and I met a, I think his wife's sister, who must live in the area, and some other lady.
[SPEAKER_02]: There were three women in the kitchen, and they were very cordial.
[SPEAKER_02]: pleasant.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, then I think we should go upstairs and talk in his den because he has some of his baseball things up there and we wouldn't be disturbing anybody else up in his room.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we went up there.
[SPEAKER_02]: The house was very nice, as I say, beautiful carpeting, very fine furniture.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what style or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just knew it was very handsome looking and everything was spotless and rather plush.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of nice windows and views out into the countryside.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lovely chairs and tables.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pictures on the walls.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know what they were now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Lovely carpeting.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was just a very comfortable and rather rich-looking house.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we went upstairs and the same kind of impression I got about the rest of the house, very rich and comfortable and well upholstered.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went into his room and there's his bedroom there and we just sat down at a desk and started in and he was very easy to interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was knowledgeable, he was good memory, expresses himself very well.
[SPEAKER_02]: picked up the questions quite readily.
[SPEAKER_02]: He did get off a little too much, I thought, on his recent scouting history, which is not of great interest to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I want to talk about his playing days, the old days.
[SPEAKER_02]: And his story about how he recruited Ernie Banks was an interesting one, but he could have been telling us so many more important things, I felt.
[SPEAKER_02]: The interview would have gone on much longer, I'm sure, if I hadn't been pressed for time.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I didn't even make an attempt to see his scrapbooks, which he mentioned towards the end of the tape there, or his pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: There are a few pictures up in the room there.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he didn't have any he could give me an autograph.
[SPEAKER_02]: He says if he gets some or if he finds some that he can spare, he will autograph one and send it to me.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it was so contrary to my morning's experience over at Ernie Shores where I walked out with just about everything Ernie Shores had.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I still have it up here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm getting ready to return the shore stuff this next week.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've gotten newspapers repaired and copied, pictures copied, and so forth.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I'm ready to return the bundle.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we'll do it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got most of the pictures copied by Phil Mazzara over in the College Information Office.
[SPEAKER_02]: About 32 7x9s made into 5x7s.
[SPEAKER_02]: Had I done this with my commercial photographer, it would have run up to $75 at least.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd say Phil did it as a favor.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I'll be sending that back this week.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't get anything, though, from Ray Hayworth.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a real good interview with Ray Hayworth, but no pictures of scrapbooks.
[SPEAKER_02]: With Ernie Shore, I had a rather poor interview, but all kinds of scrapbooks and pictures.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I guess it takes all kinds there.
[SPEAKER_02]: One thing supplements another.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was, we finished the 90 minutes and I practically, I think I closed the recorder off about that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then he started telling some stories so I slapped this present tape on to pick up a few more things.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the time was beginning to press though.
[SPEAKER_02]: The interview probably didn't get started around 2.30 after I got there around 2 and getting introduced and getting, meeting the ladies and getting upstairs, setting the recorder up.
[SPEAKER_02]: It probably wasn't about 2.30 that I
[SPEAKER_02]: got things we actually started and therefore the hour and a half interview on tape one here must have taken till around four o'clock and then I put this other one on for another 20 minutes or so and I was troubled though by the time because I had a three-hour drive ahead of me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't want to get on that bad stretch of road between Siler City and Sanford where they have no white road markers.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a newly serviced road.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't have any white markers along the
[SPEAKER_02]: outer edge of the road or the middle stripe.
[SPEAKER_02]: And driving down the previous Saturday night when we first went down to Fatville, I went off the road once, and it was nerve-wracking driving.
[SPEAKER_02]: You don't know where you are.
[SPEAKER_02]: You can't judge distances very well in the dark when there's no marking on the road.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I wanted to get back beyond that point when it got dark.
[SPEAKER_02]: Hopefully, I wanted to get all the way back.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so leaving at 4.30, I had about two hours of daylight and about an hour of darkness in driving.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I didn't linger.
[SPEAKER_02]: I did cut this thing off when there was still a lot more to be done.
[SPEAKER_02]: I kind of felt that he was glad that I was cutting it off, and although he'd like to see me again, I think he thought we'd had enough of that one session.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe not, I don't know, but the fact is I had to get going, and so I only got about an hour and 45 to an hour and 15 minutes, including the first tape, with its 90 minutes and then the 15, 20 on this one.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had a feeling, while it was a good interview, we just didn't really get into some of the meat of the matter.
[SPEAKER_02]: So much that he's done, so much he's experienced, so many people he's played with and against, that there'd be a great deal more that could be done, and with his memory as good as it is now.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was really a wonderful person and very kind and thoughtful and polite and courteous
[SPEAKER_02]: I got pictures of them after the interview was over downstairs.
[SPEAKER_02]: He and his wife stood next to the living room fireplace or mantel, and I snapped a couple of pictures of them there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said he would send me any pictures he could find, autograph them.
[SPEAKER_02]: I haven't heard from him yet, but I presume I will be hearing from him if he does find anything.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so I packed up my gear and probably left around 20 to 5 or quarter to 5 in the afternoon and drove through High Point and took a road across from High Point over to that 87, is it, or 421, the road south from Greensboro to Fayetteville.
[SPEAKER_02]: I cut a little bit of time off.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't go back up north to Route 40.
[SPEAKER_01]: I cut across and hit the road going down.
[SPEAKER_02]: And made pretty good time, and got to Sanford just about dark.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it was 6.30 now, and so I called up and told them I would be another hour or so, or another 45 minutes anyhow, coming in from Sanford.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because that was an evening we planned to go out.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were going to take Gordon and Randy out.
[SPEAKER_02]: We hadn't really, but we might.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I was calling to say we were going to be a little late for that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Gordon says other plans had been made.
[SPEAKER_02]: He answered the phone.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I finally checked in around a quarter to seven that night and spent the evening poring over the Ernie Shore stuff, which is fabulous.
[SPEAKER_02]: It seems to me that's about it now.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Ray Awerth interview, I don't know if there's much more to add.
[SPEAKER_02]: He showed me a couple of things up in his room there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some mementos of his, which are very nice.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think one of the Fort Worth team in the Texas League in 1946 or seven, he was manager there, with the pictures and names of some of the players.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a Dodger farm club.
[SPEAKER_02]: And some of the players went on to great things.
[SPEAKER_02]: He mentions Duke Snyder in particular.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had great respect for Branch Rickey.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that came out in the tape.
[SPEAKER_02]: He worked with Rickey as a Fort Worth manager and in the Dodger organization, maybe as a scout.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yes, as a scout.
[SPEAKER_02]: He scouted some of those early black players and some later ones, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I tried to get him to
[SPEAKER_02]: And he did answer the question about how he felt when Cochran came to Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he handled it very beautifully as well.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd rather be a catcher and a pennant winner than a second string catcher and a pennant winner than a first stringer on a last place team, the St. Louis Browns.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a pretty good reply.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe it's old, but it sounded good.
[SPEAKER_02]: And that's about it, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't think of anything more here on the Hayworth interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's going to leave me a whole half a tape here with nothing on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: But maybe I'll think of something one of these days.
[SPEAKER_02]: Signing off now on the 31st of March 1978.